Julius W. Becton Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Army Career, 1943-2008 (Box 6-71)
  - 7th Corps (Box 15)
    - Assumption of command, congratulatory letters, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Battalion commanders' conference, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Capstone, 1981 (Box 16)
    - "The Challenges of Leadership in an Adverse Motivational Environment," undated (Box 16)
    - Change of station, departure from 7th Corps, 1981 (Box 16)
    - Chronological file, 1961, 1974-1982, undated, (4 folders) (Box 17)
    - Cold Reason, seminar, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Commander-in-Chief, United States Army, Europe, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Commanders' conferences, 1978-1980 (Box 18)
    - Commanding general's planning calendar, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence (Box 18)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 18)
      - 1979 (Box 18)
        - Jan.-Apr., (3 folders) (Box 18)
        - May-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 19)
      - 1980 (Box 19)
      - 1981, (4 folders) (Box 20)
    - Event programs, 1979-1980 (Box 20)
    - Fact sheets, 1981 (Box 20)
    - Fifth Pacific Armies Management Seminar, 1981 (Box 20)
    - German-American relations (Box 21)
      - Greater Stuttgart Morale Support Council (Box 21)
        - Budget, 1979 (Box 21)
        - Meetings, 1979 (Box 21)
      - Miscellany, 1977-1984 (Box 21)
    - Goldman, Glen A., 1979 (Box 21)
    - Handbooks, manuals, and directives, 1978-1981 (Box 21)
    - Inactivation, 1992 (Box 21)
    - Leadership and counseling, 1978 (Box 22)
    - Notebooks, 1978-1981, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Operations manual, 1981 (Box 22)
    - Parties and entertaining, 1981 (Box 23)
    - Photographs (Box 23)
      - Henslick Range, dedication, 1983 (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 23)
    - Policies, 1979-1980 (Box 23)
    - Printed matter, 1978-1981, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Racial statistics, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Reserve Officers Training Corps, Presidents of Historically Black Colleges Conference, Tuskegee, Ala., 1980 (Box 24)
    - Schedules, 1980 (Box 24)
    - Scrapbooks, 1978-1981 See also Oversize (Box 25)
    - Speech ideas and background material, 1975-1980, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Speeches (Box 26)
      - 1978-1981, (3 folders) (Box 26)
      - 1978-1981, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - 1978-1981, (3 folders) (Box 28)
      - 1978-1981, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Telephone listings, undated (Box 29)
    - Women's issues (Box 29)
      - "Abort or Get Out" policy, 1981-1986 (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous, 1978-1981, undated (Box 29)
  - 9th Infantry Regiment (Box 30)
    - Chronological file, 1950-1951, undated, (3 folders) (Box 30)
    - L (Love) Company, 1950-1951, 1996-1998 (Box 30)
    - Miscellany, 1963, 1998-2007, undated, (2 folders) (Box 30)
  - 101st Airborne Division (Box 30)
    - 17th Cavalry Regiment (Box 30)
      - 2nd Squadron (Box 30)
        - Chronological file, 1967-1969, (2 folders) (Box 30)
        - Notebooks, 1967-1968 (Box 31)
        - Notes, 1967-1968 (Box 31)
        - Tactical standard operational procedures, 1971, undated, (3 folders) (Box 31)
      - Post-retirement (Box 31)
        - Activation ceremony, 1988 (Box 31)
        - Honorary colonel, 1988, 2001 See also Oversize (Box 32)
        - Miscellany, 1986-1995, 2000-2007 (Box 32)
        - Regimental association, 1987-1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - 3rd Brigade, 1968-1971 (Box 32)
    - Mercado, Mario M., undated (Box 32)
    - Miscellany, 1967-1969, undated (Box 32)
  - "201" file, 1943-1984, (11 folders) (Box 33)
  - Academic file (Box 33)
    - Armed Forces Staff College, Norfolk, Va., 1963-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Defense Systems Management College, Fort Belvoir, Va., 1976-1977, undated (Box 34)
    - Institute of Defense Analysis, Alexandria, Va. (Box 34)
      - Liaison officer, 1969 (Box 34)
      - Mathematical Analysis, course (Box 34)
        - Exam, 1965 (Box 34)
        - Lectures, 1968, (2 folders) (Box 34)
      - Military Planning and Modeling Concepts, course, undated, (2 folders) (Box 35)
      - Miscellany, 1966 (Box 35)
      - Operations Research, course, undated (Box 35)
        - Class material, (2 folders) (Box 35)
        - Term paper (Box 35)
      - Theory of Linear Economic Models, class, undated (Box 36)
    - National War College, Washington, D.C. (Box 36)
      - Becton, Julius W., "A Single DOD Officer Efficiency Reporting System, an Appraisal," individual research paper, 1970 (Box 36)
      - Canada and Latin America, course, 1969-1970 (Box 36)
      - Miscellany, 1951, 1970, 1977 (Box 36)
      - National Power and It's Exercise in the Modern World, course, 1969-1970 (Box 37)
      - Operations research, lectures, undated (Box 37)
      - Readings, 1968-1970 (Box 38)
      - Travel (Box 38)
        - Latin America, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 38)
        - Latin America, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 39)
        - Rio de Janeiro and Sao Paulo, Brazil, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 39)
      - United States Army Command and General Staff College, Fort Leavenworth, Kans., 1960-1964, (2 folders) (Box 39)
      - United States Army War College, Carlisle, Pa. (Box 40)
        - Board of visitors, 1988, 1996-2001, (2 folders) (Box 40)
        - Miscellany, 1965-1966, 1988 (Box 40)
        - Senior Officer Oral History Project, 1993 (Box 40)
      - University of Maryland (Box 40)
        - Theses (Box 40)
          - Becton, Julius W., 1967 (Box 40)
          - Jenista, James Francis, 1967 (Box 40)
          - Travis, William H., 1967 (Box 41)
    - Army Operational Test and Evaluation Agency (Box 41)
      - Chapel of the Four Chaplains, Philadelphia, Pa. (Box 41)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1979, undated, (3 folders) (Box 41)
      - Israel Defense Forces (Box 41)
        - Heat casualty doctrine compared with U.S. Army's, 1978 (Box 41)
        - Visit, 1977-1978 (Box 41)
      - Miscellany, 1976-1978 (Box 41)
      - Notes, undated (Box 42)
      - Officers, education and training, 1978 (Box 42)
      - Speeches, 1976-1978, undated, (2 folders) (Box 42)
      - Symposium on Women in the Army Workplace, Fort Leavenworth, Kans., 1977 (Box 42)
      - Tanks, 1977-1978, undated (Box 43)
    - Force Planning Directorate, organization chart, 1967 (Box 43)
    - Miscellany, circa 1946-1972, undated (Box 43)
    - Office of Personnel Operations, Armor Branch, 1972, undated, (4 folders) (Box 43)
    - Officer Efficiency Report System (OERS) (Box 44)
      - Army Regulation 623-105, 1968, (3 folders) (Box 44)
      - Clarke, Bruce C., 1976-1987 (Box 44)
      - Loose leaf, 1966-1969, (2 folders) (Box 44)
      - Reports and papers (Box 44)
        - Becton, Julius W., "A Single DOD Officer Efficiency Reporting System, an Appraisal," 1970 (Box 44)
        - Miscellaneous, 1969-1975, undated (Box 45)
      - "Senior Rater Update," 1989 (Box 45)
      - Study, 1975-1996, (3 folders) (Box 45)
    - Post-retirement (Box 45)
      - Army Management Staff College, Fort Belvoir, Va., circa 2004 (Box 45)
      - Bell, Anthony E., 1999 (Box 45)
      - Chaplin issues (Box 45)
        - Fort Myers Memorial Chapel, Fort Meyers, Va., 2000-2001 (Box 45)
        - Fort Myers Memorial Chapel, Fort Meyers, Va., 2000-2001 (Box 46)
        - Norris, Gary, 1998-1999 (Box 46)
        - Plummer, Henry V. (1848-1905), 2003 (Box 46)
      - Chronological file, 1983-2007, (4 folders) (Box 46)
      - Defense Science Board, Readiness Task Force, 1993-1995 (Box 46)
      - Defense Science Board, Readiness Task Force, 1993-1995, (4 folders) (Box 47)
      - Dorz, John E., 1984 (Box 47)
      - Institute for Defense Analysis, New Power versus Old Strength Seminar, 1999 (Box 47)
      - Leader to Leader Institute, Generals in Transition course, 2007 (Box 48)
      - M1E1 Abrams tank, 1983 (Box 48)
      - National Conference on Ethics in America, West Point, N.Y., 2003, (3 folders) (Box 48)
      - National Defense University, Washington, D.C., 1998 (Box 48)
      - National Guard Bureau, Strategic Issues Task Force, 2001, (2 folders) (Box 49)
      - New Manning System, 1983-1985, (3 folders) (Box 49)
      - Newspapers, 1995, 2008 (Box 49)
      - Personnel records, Becton's, 1992-1996, 2008, (3 folders) (Box 50)
      - Reading file (Box 50)
        - circa 1984-2000, (4 folder) (Box 50)
        - 2001 (Box 50)
        - 2001 (Box 51)
        - 2002-2007, undated, (2 folders) (Box 51)
      - Regimental System (Box 51)
        - 16th Infantry Regiment, 1987 (Box 51)
        - Honorary officers, 1988 (Box 51)
        - Miscellany, 1987-1988 (Box 51)
      - Secretary of the Army Resource Consultants (Box 51)
        - Loose leaf, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 51)
        - Miscellany, 1986-1992, (2 folders) (Box 52)
      - Secretary of the Army, Task Force on Extremist Activity, 1996 (Box 52)
      - Shinseki, Eric K., chief of staff, 1999 (Box 52)
      - United States Army Armor Center, Fort Knox, Ky., visit, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 52)
      - Waller, Benjamin F., nomination to command Washington, D. C. National Guard, 1989 (Box 52)
    - Printed matter, 1941-1976, (3 folders) (Box 52)
    - Promotions (Box 53)
      - Commissions, 1962-1978 (Box 53)
      - Congratulatory correspondence (Box 53)
        - 1 star (brigadier general) (Box 53)
          - A-K, 1972 (Box 53)
          - L-Z, 1972 (Box 54)
        - 2 stars (major general) (Box 54)
          - From rank of colonels and below, and civilians (Box 54)
            - A-W, 1974, (3 folders) (Box 54)
          - From general officers (Box 54)
            - A-C, 1974 (Box 54)
            - J-Z, 1974, (2 folders) (Box 55)
        - 3 stars (lieutenant general) (Box 55)
          - From friends, A-Z, 1978, (3 folders) (Box 55)
          - From general officers, A-Z, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 55)
    - Race relations (Box 55)
      - Army Equal Opportunities Initiatives, 1998 (Box 55)
      - Chronological file, 1972-1981, 1987, 1995-1998, 2004, undated, (3 folders) (Box 56)
      - Conferences, 1972, 1974, 2002, (4 folders) (Box 56)
      - Consultant briefings, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 57)
      - Fiftieth anniversary of the integration of the army, 1998 (Box 57)
      - Fred Friendly Seminars, "Affirmative Action in the Army," 2003 (Box 57)
      - Human Science Research, manuals, 1974 (Box 57)
      - Leadership and the Negro Soldier, manual, 1944 (Box 57)
      - Reports, papers, and presentations, 1980, 1995-circa 1998 (Box 57)
      - United States Army, Europe and the 7th Army, 1990-1991 (Box 57)
      - United States Army, Europe and the 7th Army, 1990-1991 (Box 58)
    - Reserve Officers Training Corps, 1965-1965 (Box 58)
    - Retirement, 1983 (Box 58)
      - Apr.-Aug., (4 folders) (Box 58)
      - Sept.-Nov. (Box 59)
    - Selective Service System, 2000 (Box 59)
    - Training and Doctrine Command (Box 59)
      - Armor conference, Fort Knox, Ky., 1981 (Box 59)
      - Combat clothing and equipment, 1981 (Box 59)
      - Correspondence (Box 59)
        - 1979 (Box 59)
        - 1981 (Box 59)
          - June-Oct., (4 folders) (Box 59)
          - Nov.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 60)
        - 1982 (Box 60)
          - Jan.-Apr., (5 folders) (Box 60)
          - May-Nov., (8 folders) (Box 61)
          - Dec., (2 folders) (Box 62)
        - 1983 (Box 62)
          - Jan.-May, (5 folders) (Box 62)
          - June-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 63)
      - Delta Force, 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 63)
      - Division 86, 1980-1981 (Box 64)
      - Educational Broadcasting Company, The Black American Soldier, documentary film, 1982 (Box 64)
      - Gifts and mementos, 1979, undated (Box 64)
      - Hermes, Peter, 1981-1982 (Box 64)
      - "Low Intensity Conflict," 1983 (Box 64)
      - Initial Entry Training Publications, 1979-1981 (Box 64)
      - Miscellany, 1981-1983 See also Oversize (Box 65)
      - Notes, 1981-1982 (Box 65)
      - Physical fitness programs, 1983 (Box 65)
      - Prairie View A&M University, visit, 1983 (Box 66)
      - Printed matter, 1981-1983 (Box 66)
      - ROTC Professionalism and Military Professional Ethics, course, 1981 (Box 66)
      - Speeches (Box 66)
        - 1981 (Box 66)
        - 1982 (Box 66)
          - Jan.-Oct., (2 folders) (Box 66)
          - Dec. (Box 67)
        - 1983-1984, undated, (2 folders) (Box 67)
      - Sperry Army Training System, undated (Box 67)
      - Tank firing test, 1981 (Box 67)
      - Teletypes (Box 67)
        - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 67)
        - Rogers, Charles C., 1981-1982 (Box 67)
      - Training devices and range facilities, 1981 (Box 67)
      - United States Army Center of Military History, 1986-1987 (Box 68)
      - "Where Have We Been and Where We Ought to Go," memo, Howard G. Crowell, major general, 1981 (Box 68)
    - United States Army Training Center, Fort Dix, N.J. (Box 68)
      - Commandership and management, 1973-1974 (Box 68)
      - Correspondence (Box 68)
        - Christmas, 1973 (Box 68)
        - General (Box 68)
          - 1972 (Box 68)
          - 1973 (Box 68)
            - Jan.-Oct. (Box 68)
            - Nov.-Dec. (Box 69)
          - 1974-1976 (Box 69)
        - "Sick" letters, 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 69)
      - Enlisted evaluation system, 1972 (Box 69)
      - Miscellany, 1972-1975, 1981 (Box 69)
      - Newspapers and newspaper clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 69)
      - Notebooks, 1972-1976 (Box 70)
      - Speeches, 1973-1975 (Box 70)
      - Surveys (Box 70)
        - Enlisted aide, 1973-1974 (Box 70)
        - First tour performance discipline research, 1972 (Box 70)
      - Visits (Box 70)
        - Burlington Township High School, Burlington, N. J., undated (Box 70)
        - Bryn Mawr Elementary School, Bryn Mawr, Pa., 1974 (Box 70)
        - Lower Merion High School, Ardmore, Pa., visit by Becton classmates to Fort Dix, N. J. 1974 (Box 71)
        - United States Army Aviation Center and School, Fort Rucker, Ala., 1974 (Box 71)
- Office of Foreign Disaster Assistance, 1984-2004 (Box 71-76)
  Correspondence, speeches, handbooks, reports, notebooks, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or topic.
  - "Action Officer's Handbook," 1985 (Box 71)
  - African famine, 1984-1985 (Box 71)
  - Annual report, 2003 (Box 71)
  - Appointment book, 1984 (Box 71)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1988, 1995, (6 folders) (Box 72)
  - Deputy director for Africa relief, handbook, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 73)
  - "Disaster History, Significant Date on Major Disasters Worldwide, 1900-Present," 1985 (Box 73)
  - "Disaster Relief Assistance & Related Data," 1985 (Box 73)
  - Ghana, visit, 1984 (Box 74)
  - Miscellany, 1984-1986, 2003 (Box 74)
  - Notebooks, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 74)
  - Olson, Richard S., "USAID's Office of U.S. Foreign Disaster Assistance (OFDA): A Critical Juncture Analysis," 2002 (Box 75)
  - Red Cross, 1984-1989 (Box 75)
  - Speeches (Box 75)
    - 1984 (Box 75)
    - 1985 (Box 75)
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders) (Box 75)
      - Apr.-Oct., undated, (2 folders) (Box 76)
    - 2004 (Box 76)
  - Transition meetings, undated (Box 76)
- Federal Emergency Management Agency, 1954-2007 (Box 76-97)
  Correspondence, speeches, printed matter, government records, North Atlantic Treaty Organization records, reports, project files, topical files, travel files, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material, title of conference or report, or topic.
  - Advisory Board (Box 76)
    - 1987-1989 (Box 76)
    - 1990-2007, (2 folders) (Box 77)
  - American Red Cross, 1988-1989, (2 folders) (Box 77)
  - Appointment books, 1986-1989 (Box 77)
  - Articles, 1986-1996, 2002-2006, (2 folders) (Box 77)
  - Award ceremonies, 1987-1989 (Box 78)
  - Biographical sketches, FEMA staff, 1985-1988 (Box 78)
  - Conference on Civil Defense in the Nuclear Age, 1989 (Box 78)
  - Chronological file, 1981-1989, (2 folders) (Box 78)
  - Congressional file (Box 78)
    - Hearings, 1978-1988, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - Reports, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 79)
  - Correspondence (Box 79)
    - 1985, (3 folders) (Box 79)
    - 1986 (Box 79)
      - Jan.-May (Box 79)
      - June-Oct., (3 folders) (Box 80)
    - 1987 (Box 80)
      - Jan.-Aug., (3 folders) (Box 80)
      - Sept.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - 1988 (Box 81)
      - Jan.-Nov., (5 folders) (Box 81)
      - Dec. (Box 81)
      - Dec. (Box 82)
    - 1989, (4 folders) (Box 82)
    - 1990-2001, (2 folders) (Box 82)
  - Executive orders and regulations, 1979-1988, 1995 (Box 82)
  - "The FEMA Story," scrapbook, undated See Oversize (Box 82)
  - Holcomb, Staser, 2001 (Box 82)
  - Issue and discussion papers, 1984, 1989 (Box 82)
  - Log, invitation to conferences and speaking engagements, 1986-1988 (Box 83)
  - Meetings (Box 83)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1989 (Box 83)
    - Third quarter program review, 1989 (Box 83)
  - Miscellany, 1984-1989, 2004-2005 See also Oversize, (2 folders) (Box 83)
  - National Academy of Public Administration, 1988-1993, (2 folders) (Box 83)
  - National Defense Executive Reserve, 1988-1995 (Box 84)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1984-1992, 2005-2006 (Box 84)
  - Nomination and appointment, 1985 (Box 84)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (Box 84)
    - Chronological file, 1954-1991 See also Classified, (3 folders) (Box 84)
    - Loose leafs, 1976-1990 See also Classified, (6 folders) (Box 85)
    - Speech, 1990 (Box 86)
  - Notebooks, 1985-1990, (3 folders) (Box 86)
  - Presidential Classroom program, 1987-1988 (Box 86)
  - Presidential inauguration, 1988-1989 (Box 87)
  - Press statements and interviews with Julius W. and Louise Becton, 1985-1987 (Box 87)
  - Printed matter, 1984-1993 (Box 87)
  - Publications by FEMA (Box 87)
    - Manuals, 1986-1988, (3 folders) (Box 87)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 87)
      - 1983-1988 (Box 87)
      - 1989-1991, 2006 (Box 88)
  - Regions, 1988-1999, (2 folders) (Box 88)
  - Reports, 1983-1989 (Box 88)
  - Retirement, 1989, (2 folders) (Box 88)
  - "Role of the Black Media in Disaster Reporting to the Black Community," 1986 (Box 88)
  - Speeches (Box 89)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 89)
    - 1986 (Box 89)
      - Jan.-May, (6 folders) (Box 89)
      - June-Oct., (6 folders) (Box 90)
      - Nov.-Dec. (Box 91)
    - 1987 (Box 91)
      - Jan.-Mar., (4 folders) (Box 91)
      - Apr.-Aug. See also Oversize, (7 folders) (Box 92)
      - Sept. (Box 92)
      - Sept. (Box 93)
      - Oct.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 93)
    - 1988 (Box 93)
      - Jan.-Mar., (4 folders) (Box 93)
      - Apr.-Sept., (6 folders) (Box 94)
      - Oct.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 95)
    - 1989 (Box 95)
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders) (Box 95)
      - Apr.-Sept., (3 folders) (Box 96)
    - 2003 (Box 96)
  - Terrorism Timeline: Major Terrorism Events and Their U.S. Outcomes (1988-2001), Claire B. Rubin and others, 2003 (Box 96)
  - Thursday Luncheon Group, 1984-1988 (Box 96)
  - Transitions (Box 96)
    - 1985 (Box 96)
    - 1988 (Box 96)
  - Trips, 1988-1989 (Box 97)
  - United States Fire Administration, 1986-1995 (Box 97)
  - Visitors, logs, 1985-1987 (Box 97)
  - World Trade Center attack, 2002 (Box 97)
- Prairie View A&M University, 1966-2007 (Box 97-127)
  Correspondence, speeches, legal case files, newspapers and newspaper clippings, notebooks and notes, organizational records, reports, topical files, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
  - Agriculture, 1990-1994 (Box 97)
  - American Petroleum Institute, Crisis Seminar, 1993, (2 folders) (Box 97)
  - Appointment, inauguration, and early administration (Box 97)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 97)
    - First year, notebooks, 1984-1992, (4 folders) (Box 98)
    - Greetings from other colleges and universities, 1990 (Box 98)
    - Homecoming, 1990 (Box 98)
    - Inauguration ceremony, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 98)
    - Powell, Colin, 1990 (Box 99)
    - Texas A&M System, 1989-1990 (Box 99)
  - Athletic program, 1980-2007, (3 folders) (Box 99)
  - Chronological file (Box 99)
    - 1985 (Box 99)
    - 1989, Jan.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - 1990 (Box 99)
      - Jan.-Apr. (Box 99)
      - May-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 100)
    - 1991 (Box 100)
      - Jan.-Sept., (3 folders) (Box 100)
      - Oct.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - 1992 (Box 101)
      - Jan.-Nov., (5 folders) (Box 101)
      - Dec. (Box 102)
    - 1993 (Box 102)
      - Jan.-Oct., (5 folders) (Box 102)
      - Nov.-Dec., circa 1993, (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - 1994 (Box 103)
      - Jan.-Nov., (4 folders) (Box 103)
      - Dec., circa 1994, (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - 1995-1998, 2004-2005, (6 folders) (Box 104)
  - Class of 1940, reunion, 1990 (Box 105)
  - Employees, 1990, undated (Box 105)
  - General Julius W. Becton, Jr. Auditorium, 2006 (Box 105)
  - Historically black colleges and universities (Box 105)
    - Miscellany, 1982-1993, (4 folders) (Box 105)
    - National Association for Equal Opportunity in Higher Education, 1988 See Oversize (Box 105)
    - White House Initiatives on Historically Black Colleges and Universities, 1990, 2000 (Box 105)
  - Interviews with Julius and Louise Becton, 1993 (Box 106)
  - Legal file (Box 106)
    - Davis v. Prairie View A&M, 1995 (Box 106)
    - Israni v. Becton, 1995, (3 folders) (Box 106)
    - Knight v. State of Alabama (Box 106)
      - Calhoun Community College, Tanner, Ala., 1995 (Box 106)
      - Court history, 1991, (2 folders) (Box 106)
      - Court history, 1991 (Box 107)
      - Miscellany, 1995-1999, 2006, (2 folders) (Box 107)
      - Index and log, 1994 (Box 107)
      - Numerical file (Box 107)
        - Nos. 1/1-1/21, (3 folders) (Box 107)
        - Nos. 1/22- 1/69, (8 folders) (Box 108)
        - Nos. 1/70-1/98E, (5 folders) (Box 109)
        - Nos. 1/98F-1/131, (6 folders) (Box 110)
        - Nos. 1/132-1/142, (6 folders) (Box 111)
        - Nos. 1/143-4/8, (7 folders) (Box 112)
        - Nos. 4/9-6/57, (6 folders) (Box 113)
    - Waugh v. Prairie View A&M (Box 113)
    - Waugh v. Prairie View A&M, (4 folders) (Box 114)
  - Miscellany, 1969-1994, 2000 (Box 114)
  - Newspaper clippings and news magazines, 1983-2007 (Box 114)
  - Newspapers (Box 114)
    - Miscellaneous, 1989-2007 (Box 114)
    - The Panther, 1973-1995 (Box 115)
  - Notebooks and notes, 1990-1993, undated, (3 folders) (Box 115)
  - Notebooks and notes, 1990-1993, undated, (2 folders) (Box 116)
  - Post-presidency (Box 116)
    - Chronological file (Box 116)
      - 1995-2000, (5 folders) (Box 116)
      - 2001-2007, (7 folders) (Box 117)
    - College of Nursing, 1999, (3 folders) (Box 118)
  - Prairie View A&M University Foundation, 1994-1996, (2 folders) (Box 118)
  - Prairie View A&M University National Alumni Association (Box 118)
    - 1987-2004, (2 folders) (Box 118)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 119)
  - Presidential transition report, 1994, (2 folders) (Box 119)
  - Presidential search, 1994, (3 folders) (Box 119)
  - Printed matter (Box 120)
    - By Prairie View A&M University (Box 120)
      - Catalogues and class schedules, 1990-1994 (Box 120)
      - Commencement convocations, 1990-1995 (Box 120)
      - Fact books (Box 120)
        - 1983-1995, (3 folders) (Box 120)
        - 1991-2003, (2 folders) (Box 121)
      - Miscellaneous, 1966-2007, (4 folders) (Box 121)
    - By other institutions (Box 121)
  - Retirement (Box 122)
    - "Book of Memories," 1994 See Oversize (Box 122)
    - Cards, 1994, (2 folders) (Box 122)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 122)
    - Farewell scholarship banquet, 1994 (Box 122)
  - Speeches (Box 122)
    - 1966, 1980, 1990 See also Oversize, (3 folders)
    - 1991 (Box 122)
      - Jan. (Box 122)
      - Feb. (Box 122)
        - 9-11 (Box 122)
        - 15-23, (2 folders) (Box 123)
      - Mar.-Nov., (4 folders) (Box 123)
    - 1992, (4 folders) (Box 124)
    - 1993 (Box 124)
      - Jan.-Feb., (2 folders) (Box 124)
      - June-Nov., (2 folders) (Box 125)
    - 1994, (4 folders) (Box 125)
    - 1995-2007, (5 folders) (Box 126)
  - Strategic planning retreat, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 126)
  - Strategic planning retreat, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 127)